Richfield Oil Corporation and the Oil Workers' International Union Records 5372
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Richfield Oil Corporation and the Oil Workers' International Union Records
1954-1955
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Richfield Oil Corporation
Oil Workers' International Union
5372
0.5 cubic feet
0.5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Briefs and petitions in the case of Richfield Oil Corporation and Oil Workers International Union before the National Labor Relations Board, 1954, and Richfield Oil Corporation vs. NLRB, United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, 1955.
5620111
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 10, 2005
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 11, 2019
Biographical / Historical
An NLRB case involving the expansion of the area of compulsory bargainable issues. The company had unilaterally promulgated a Stock Purchase Plan and had refused to bargain with the union over it, claiming that is not encompassed by the terms "wages" or "other conditions of employment" within the meaning of the National Labor Relations Act, but is merely an incentive to employees voluntarily to invest in company stock.
Upon charges of unfair labor practices filed by the Union the General Counsel of the NLRB by the Regional Direcotr for the Twenty- First Region (Los Angeles) issued a complaint on November 16, 1953 against the Company. In February, 1954 all parties entered into a stipulation which set forth an agreed statement of facts and executed a Motion to Transfer Proceeding to the Board, in which the parties waived their right to a hearing and the issuance of an Intermediate Report, etc. The Board then heard oral arguement on July 22, 1954. A decision in favor of the Union was handed down on October I8, 1954 stating that stock purchase plans were a bargainable issue, not a managerial prerogative; because, according to its interpretation, "wages" comprehends all emoluments of value which may accrue to employees because of their employment relationship.
The Company then appealed to the District of Columbia - Circuit Court of Appeals, which upheld the decision of the NLRB, and finally to the U.S. Supreme Court, which denied certiorari.
Scope and Contents
Briefs and petitions in the case of Richfield Oil Corporation and Oil Workers International Union before the National Labor Relations Board, 1954, and Richfield Oil Corporation vs. NLRB, United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit, 1955.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Oil industry workers -- Labor unions.; Collective labor agreements -- Oil industries; Stock options.; Richfield Oil Corporation.; Oil Workers International Union.
5620111
- Stipulation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Before the NLRB
- Brief, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Brief of Richfield Oil Corporation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Union's Brief, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Richfield's Reply to Brief of Oil Workers International Union, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Reply Brief by General Counsel, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Union's Reply Brief, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Supplemental Brief for Respondent, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Exhibits, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Decision and Order, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Petition to Review an Order of the NLRB, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  Before the Court of Appeals
- Brief for the Chamber of Commerce, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Brief for National Association of Manufacturers, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Brief for American Retail Federation, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Brief for Petitioner, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Petition for a Writ of Certiorari, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  Before the Supreme Court
- Brief of the NAM as Araicus Curiae in Support of the Petition for Writ of Certiorari, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 17)